(upbeat music)
- Hello, English learners, welcome
back to English Pod, my name is Marco.
- And I'm Erica.
- Today we're bringing you part two
of another great lesson that we had.
- Yes, new guy in town.
- And new guy in town.
- Part two.
- Kind of a creepy story.
- Yes.
- Yeah, and this one is also a
little bit strange, a little bit weird.
- Yeah, unusual outcome, unusual ending.
- But it has to do a lot with invitations.
- That's right, so an invitation is when
you ask somebody to do something with you.
- Right, a dinner invitation.
- So we're gonna be talking about
invitations and inviting people to do things.
- Okay.
- Well with that, let's listen to
the dialogue for the first time.
(upbeat music)
- Oh, Arman, thank you for
such a thoughtful invitation.
It's really very nice of you
to invite us over for dinner.
Don't you think so, Ellen?
- Oh, yes, of course.
We'd love to come over.
- Can I bring anything?
- No, don't worry about it.
I'll take care of everything.
I'll see you tonight.
Come with an appetite.
- I know I will.
- I don't want to go over
to his place for dinner.
He gives me the creeps.
Why an earth did you accept?
- Well, come on, Ellen.
It'll be nice to get to know him besides.
He's new to the neighborhood and
it'll be rude to decline his invitation.
- I guess so.
You always wrote me into things like this.
(upbeat music)
- Ladies.
- Thank you for coming.
You look delicious.
I mean, beautiful.
Please come in.
- Oh, Ireland, you're too kind.
- How did I get myself into this?
(upbeat music)
- Wow, I'm really anxious to see
what happens in this dinner party.
- Yeah, I guess we'll have to stay
tuned and find out for part three.
- Yeah.
- All right, well, we have
some really great vocabulary,
so I guess we can start
with language takeaway.
- Language takeaway.
- All right, on language takeaway
today, we have three great words.
Erica, why don't you start
us off with the first one?
- The first word is thoughtful.
- Thoughtful.
- So when you're
thoughtful, you're kind, right?
- You're kind, you're
considerate to other people.
- You think about what
the other person would like.
- Right.
- And you do that thing.
- It's so thoughtful of you.
- Yeah.
- Our second phrase, give me the creeps.
Give me the creeps.
- This is kind of a funny
phrase, but I think if we
listen to some examples,
we'll understand the meaning.
- Example one.
- Horror movies give me the creeps.
- Example two.
Stop it, you're giving me the creeps.
- Example three.
- I saw this really scary clown.
It gave me the creeps.
- So I can see this one means
to make me feel uncomfortable.
- Right, it makes me feel scared.
- Yeah, scared.
- Just me the creeps.
And our last phrase for
language takeaway, rope me into.
- Rope me into something.
So if you rope me into
something, it's like you convince me
to do something that I
don't really want to do.
- Right, so I roped you
into lending me your car.
- Yes.
- That was a bad idea.
- And you wrote me into
going out for beers afterward.
- Yeah, that was a great idea.
- All right, so rope me into convince.
- Yeah.
- All righty, so I guess we could
listen to our dialogue again.
- This time, a little bit
slower, and you'll be able
to understand the language
a little bit more clearly.
(upbeat music)
- Oh, Armand, thank you for
such a thoughtful invitation.
It's really very nice of you
to invite us over for dinner.
Don't you think so, Ellen?
- Oh, yes, of course.
We'd love to come over.
Can I bring anything?
- No, don't worry about it.
I'll take care of everything.
I'll see you tonight.
Come with an appetite.
I know I will.
- I don't want to go over
to his place for dinner.
He gives me the creeps.
Why on earth did you accept?
- Oh, come on, Ellen.
It will be nice to get to know him.
Besides, he's new to the neighborhood, and
it will be rude to decline his invitation.
- I guess so.
You always wrote me into things like this.
- Ladies, thank you for coming.
You look delicious.
I mean, beautiful, please come in, come in.
- Oh, Armand, you are too kind.
- How did I get myself into this?
- Well, I guess that's a lot more clear
and with that, we can start
putting it together today.
- Putting it together.
- Today, we've got three words and phrases
that we want to show you how you
can put together and use differently.
The first one is appetite.
- Appetite.
- Appetite is like a strong
desire for food, right?
- Right, an appetite.
We've got some examples that
show you how to use this phrase.
Let's listen.
- Example one.
- Mm, dinner smells so good.
It's giving me an appetite.
- Example two.
- You're sure eating a lot.
You must have a big appetite.
- Example three.
- I'm getting sick.
I have a fever and I lost my appetite.
- Okay, so we saw some
great examples of appetite.
You can lose your appetite.
- That's right.
- You have a big appetite.
- Small appetite.
- A healthy appetite.
- Right.
So it just means a desire for food.
- Desire for food.
- Yeah.
- Great, what's our
second phrase for today?
- Get to know someone.
- Get to know.
- So when you get to know someone is you
talk to them and you find out what they do.
- Yeah, you get more familiar with that.
- More familiar, right?
For example, we can
say I got to know her in
Spanish class and she's
a really nice person.
- Yeah, or you can say
Armand, Ellen and Doris
got to know each
other at a dinner party.
- Right.
- You can say if you get to know
me, you'll see that I'm not a bad guy.
- Yeah, that's true.
- Okay, get to know.
- And our third phrase is why on earth?
- Why on earth?
This is like a saying expression.
- You can use it in a
lot of different ways.
So we've got some examples for you.
Let's listen.
- Example one.
- Where is my phone?
- Example two.
- How on earth did you
learn English in one month?
- Example three.
- What on earth is it?
- So when you ask a question
with on earth, so why on earth?
How on earth?
What on earth?
- It's like you're
showing a lot of surprise.
- Okay, great stuff.
So let's just listen to
our dialogue a third time.
- Oh, Arman, thank you for
such a thoughtful invitation.
It's really very nice of you
to invite us over for dinner.
Don't you think so, Ellen?
- Oh, yes, of course.
We'd love to come over.
Can I bring anything?
- No, don't worry about it.
I'll take care of everything.
I'll see you tonight come with an appetite.
- I know I will.
- I don't want to go over
to his place for dinner.
He gives me the creeps.
Why on earth did you accept?
- Well, come on, Ellen.
It'll be nice to get to know him besides.
He's new to the neighborhood and
it'll be rude to decline his invitation.
- I guess so.
You always wrote me into things like this.
(gentle music)
- Ladies.
- Thank you for coming.
You look delicious.
I mean, beautiful.
Please, come in.
- Oh, Arman, you are too kind.
How did I get myself into this?
(gentle music)
- We want to know what
you think happens next.
- Yes, what happens in this dialogue next?
- So we want you to
send us your idea of what
happens next and we're
going to choose the best one.
- That's right, Marco and I will choose
the best continuation of the story
and we'll use that in part
three of the new guy in town.
- That's right.
So you can give it any direction you want.
- And of course we'll publish the
name of the author with the lesson.
- Yes.
- I'm really anxious to see what ideas
come up and how we can end this dialogue.
- I know we've got a lot of
really creative users out there.
So I'm really looking forward to this.
- That's right, that's right.
So be sure to send us your
ideas, either a private message
or you can post it on the
comments section of this lesson
and any other questions
or doubts, go to englishpot.
com and you can
leave them there.
- Yes, Marco and I are always
happy to answer your questions.
- Okay folks, so until then, it's goodbye.
- Bye.
(upbeat music)